# **EMMA BINDI**

## **ABOUT**

Enthusiastic, self-starting and highly organised finance and procurement professional with all-round administration and project support experience.

A cheerful and kind individual with strong communication skills and an energising can-do attitude, I thrive in environments that require autonomy and meticulous attention to detail.

I take initiative wherever I work, proactively identify problems and opportunities, deliver accurate and complete work fast, and contribute to the culture and people around me.

## CONTACT

emma.bindi@outlook.com

0404 606 182

Prahran, VIC 3181

Australian Citizen

## **EDUCATION**

## BACHELOR OF COMMERCE: ACCOUNTING

2011

Curtin University, Perth WA

## PROJECT MANAGEMENT FUNDAMENTALS

2018

Aust. Institute of Management, WA

## EXPERIENCE

### **PURCHASING OFFICER**

Shark Bay Salt | Dec 2016 to June 2019

Provision of holistic purchasing services for two remote salt mines

Delivery of end to end procurement ensuring cost effective and expedient supply of all goods and services. Management of inventory database in ERP, carrying out re-order function and maintaining catalogue.

Reporting and analysis of inventory catalogue baskets for supply and pricing negotiations. Liaising with new and existing suppliers, service providers & key stakeholders to ensure best price, availability & quality requirements are achieved. Contracts preparation and execution for all projects works and large capital purchases. Manage vendor contracts and performance database including document management. Logistics co-ordination for inbound and outbound freight to remote mine sites. Building management liaison for Perth head office and management of office supplies and equipment.

- Created and implemented a vendor evaluation management register and procedure following on from ISO9001 audit and certification
- Active member of Supply Chain Efficiency Committee, coordinated organisation-wide resources to support project delivery and business improvement activities
- Led initiative to overhaul existing ERP forms and transmission method including re-design of new Purchase Order, Request for Quote and Payment Remittance templates, liaised with external IT consultant to ensure smooth digital transition
- Nominated as 1 of 4 (out of 200 staff) for Pronto Subject Matter Expert to provide first point of call assistance and training for organisation-wide staff

## **PROJECT ASSISTANT & FINANCE ALL ROUNDER**

BallPoint Construction | April 2015 to Dec 2016

Executed broad range of project support and accounting functions for a construction company undergoing rapid expansion

Daily project support to construction manager and engineer from procurement of goods through to scheduling of sub-contractors. Tracking project milestones & deliveries and keeping relevant personnel up to date. Weekly project reporting for progress claim calculations, variance analysis and cost to complete forecasts.

Manage complete administration function for all tenders from EOI through to final presentation including marketing materials preparation.

Raising of purchase orders and maintenance of sub-contractor documentation database. Contract preparation and management. Administration for all government licenses and permits.

Delivery of end to end Accounts Payable and Receivable, as well as HR duties including fortnightly payroll, superannuation and on-boarding activities.

- Coordinated tender submissions through cost calculations, vendor liaison, compilation and formatting
- Led business through technical transition from MYOB to Xero, including setup of chart of accounts and training junior accounts clerk
- Created of budget tracking and progress claim calculation worksheets and procedure to accurately track and record project expenditure

# **EMMA BINDI**

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Xero
MYOB
MS Outlook, Excel, Word, Project
BGL Simple Fund
Pronto XI ERP

## PERSONAL INTERESTS

Hiking

Reading

**Pilates** 

Mountain Biking

Volunteering (Mobile Laundry Service for Homeless)

## REFERENCES

## **ANDREW BARNES**

Senior Purchasing Officer Shark Bay Salt 0439 351 723

## **GLEN STANLEY**

Registered Manager Shark Bay Salt 0407 103 759

### **TYRONE KENNEDY**

Engineer & Project Manager BallPoint Construction 0403 739 852

## EXPERIENCE CONT'D

#### **OVERSEAS TRAVEL 2014 TO 2015**

### **BOOKKEEPER**

Gecko Bookkeeping | 2013 to 2014

Provision of complete accounts support to businesses from several industries

Delivery of weekly management reports. End to end processing of Accounts Payable and Receivable. Payroll processing including leave requests, terminations, lodgement of payroll tax returns and superannuation. Preparation and lodgement of BAS and liaison with ATO on behalf of clients. Ad hoc administration including document filing.

- Created and implemented automated payroll spreadsheet for a large hotel, restaurant and brewery group, this required interpretation of applicable industry awards
- Provided training in use of Xero for small business owners
- Transitioned multiple businesses from MYOB to Xero including setup of chart of accounts and form design

### **TAX ACCOUNTANT**

Marlston Taxation | 2012 to 2013

Provide professional accounting services for partnerships, trusts, unlisted and ASX listed companies, SMSFs and consolidated tax groups

Prepare financial statements and income tax returns from MYOB transactions. Carry out end of year backup and roll overs.

Processing end of year data for self-managed super funds. Assist with setup of new companies including all ASIC requirements. Preparation of BAS and FBT returns as well as liaison with ATO on behalf of clients.

• Implemented use of new software within the firm, BGL Simple Fund

## **TAX ACCOUNTANT**

Ernst & Young | 2010 to 2012

Provide professional accounting services for high wealth individuals, family business groups and R&D enterprises.

Processing end of year data and preparing adjusting journals through to draft presentation of financial statements and income tax returns. Preparation of individual tax returns, involving collation of high volume share trading registers and capital gains tax calculations.

Assistance with cash flow forecasts and tax estimates for clients. Preparation of BAS and FBT returns.

## **MOBILE BOOKKEEPER**

Admin Express | 2009 to 2010

Manage full function bookkeeping on behalf of various small businesses.

End to end processing of Accounts Payable and Receivable using MYOB. Full transaction processing including bank reconciliations, general journals and monthly accruals. Complete payroll processing including superannuation lodgements and PAYG payment summaries. Lodgement of BAS.